<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Native Platform – Cloud Native Platform for Government</title><link>https://govcloud.ca/</link><description>Recent Hugo news from gohugo.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><image><url>https://govcloud.ca/img/hugo.png</url><title>GoHugo.io</title><link>https://govcloud.ca/</link></image><atom:link href="https://govcloud.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Government of Canada Enterprise Architecture Review Board</title><link>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2020/01/17/government-of-canada-enterprise-architecture-review-board/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2020/01/17/government-of-canada-enterprise-architecture-review-board/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The cloud native team presented to the Government of Canada Enterprise Architecture Review Board. The presentation was well recieved with quite a few statements being really supportive of the architecture and even making reference that this is exactly what would be done in the private space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, some of the members who were working on the Amazon cloud service provider were keen to provide help and will be making a pull request so it can be supported as well. The meeting ended with GC EARB endorsing the architecture and asking us to present at an upcoming meeting of OneGC where a more technical deep dive can occur.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">The Enterprise Architecture Review Board just endorsed an open-source architecture that allows more flexibility in creating, publishing and managing web content. Novel ideas lead to big results under &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/OneGC?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#OneGC&lt;/a>! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GCDigital?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GCDigital&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WCMS?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WCMS&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&amp;mdash; Digital Enablement (@DigiEnablement) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DigiEnablement/status/1218334608116285440?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 18, 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8">&lt;/script>
&lt;h2 id="main-presentation">Main Presentation&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://govcloud.blob.core.windows.net/docs/azure-aks-infra.pdf">Azure Reference Architecture&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://govcloud.blob.core.windows.net/docs/azure-aks-platform.pdf">Azure Kubernetes Service Platform&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://govcloud.blob.core.windows.net/docs/architecture.pdf">Drupal Architecture&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://govcloud.blob.core.windows.net/docs/architecture-links.txt">Drupal Architecture Links&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="other-links">Other Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/canada-ca-terraform-modules/terraform-kubernetes-aks">Terraform for AKS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/canada-ca-terraform-modules/terraform-kubernetes-aks-platform">Terraform for AKS Platform&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/drupalwxt/helm-drupal">Helm chart for Drupal WxT&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/drupalwxt/terraform-containers-webapp-azure">Terraform for Azure Web Apps Containers&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://software.af.mil/dsop/documents/">US Department of Defense DevSecOps&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: Digital Academy course on Cloud Native</title><link>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/12/17/digital-academy-course-on-cloud-native/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/12/17/digital-academy-course-on-cloud-native/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The team presented a two-day course at the School of Public Service’s Digital Academy on Docker Containers, Kubernetes
and Cloud Native technologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The course was attended by employees of various Government of Canada departments. The course included course material
and interactive labs, which reinforced the content that was presented.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: KubeCon 2019 in San Diego</title><link>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/11/19/kubecon-2019-in-san-diego/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/11/19/kubecon-2019-in-san-diego/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The team have all returned home after another great KubeCon NA, and we thoroughly enjoyed our time in sunny San Diego.
We got to attend lots of amazing sessions, held many insightful conversations at the various booths, and learned quite a
bit from the phenomenal community. We tried where possible to share some of our reflections and insights learned each
day which has been refined into a list of key takeaways.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Kubernetes needs a Ruby on Rails moment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Vendors are moving up the stack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CNCF community is amazing, but the tech can be challenging&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Multi-cloud is big business&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Diverging Workflows: GitOps vs UI-driven&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Blog: AKS infratructure v0.1 release</title><link>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/11/15/aks-infratructure-v0.1-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/11/15/aks-infratructure-v0.1-release/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Text to be added here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: AKS Platform v0.1 release</title><link>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/10/15/aks-platform-v0.1-release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/10/15/aks-platform-v0.1-release/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Text to be added here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: IKS infratructure v0.1 release</title><link>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/10/15/iks-infratructure-v0.1-release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/10/15/iks-infratructure-v0.1-release/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Text to be added here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: IKS Platform v0.1 release</title><link>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/10/15/iks-platform-v0.1-release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/10/15/iks-platform-v0.1-release/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Text to be added here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Stratosphere 2019 in Ottawa</title><link>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/06/20/stratosphere-2019-in-ottawa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2019/06/20/stratosphere-2019-in-ottawa/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Government of Canada (GC), in partnership with Association of Public Sector Information Professionals (DPI), is hosting Stratosphere, a conference focused on Cloud and DevOps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The adoption of Cloud, and more recently, DevOps, have become growing themes amongst GC IT professionals. This conference is an opportunity for participants to share their experiences and lessons learned with their peers, and for the GC IT community to learn about possible partnerships with industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Where: The Shaw Centre, Downtown Ottawa&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When: June 20th, 2019&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Who: Employees of the Government of Canada&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fees: None, free for all GC employees&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="presentation">Presentation&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Title: Kubernetes + containers ecosystem, CNCF, Security with Istio Service Mesh, KNative and Serverless, Open Policy Agent&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Room: 209 - DevOps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Time: 10:00 - 10:30&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: Cloud Native Architecture</title><link>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2018/12/18/cloud-native-architecture/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://govcloud.ca/blog/2018/12/18/cloud-native-architecture/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="cloud-native">Cloud Native&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A cloud native application is a distributed, elastic and horizontal scalable system composed of (micro)services which
isolates state in a minimum of stateful components. The application and each self contained deployment unit of that
application is designed according to cloud-focused design patterns and operated on a self service elastic platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Note: Even though the specific tools and patterns may differ, cloud-native organizations and applications follow a
fairly consistent pattern.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>At its most fundamental level a cloud native application is engineered to run on a cloud platform and is designed for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Resiliency&lt;/strong>: Embraces failures instead of trying to prevent them; it takes advantage of the dynamic nature of
running on a cloud platform&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Agility&lt;/strong>: Allows for fast deployments and quick iterations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Operability&lt;/strong>: Adds control of application life cycles from inside the application instead of relying on external
processes and monitors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Observability&lt;/strong>: Provides information to answer questions about application state&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="cloud-native-infrastructure">Cloud Native Infrastructure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cloud native infrastructure is infrastructure that is hidden behind useful abstractions, controlled by APIs, managed by
software, and has the purpose of running applications. Running infrastructure with these traits gives rise to a new
pattern for managing that infrastructure in a scalable, efficient way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstractions are useful when they successfully hide complexity for their consumer. They can enable more complex uses of
the technology, but they also limit how the technology is used. They apply to low-level technology, such as how TCP
abstracts IP, or higher levels, such as how VMs abstract physical servers. Abstractions should always allow the consumer
to &lt;strong>“move up the stack”&lt;/strong> and not reimplement the lower layers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cloud native infrastructure needs to abstract the underlying IaaS offerings to provide its own abstractions. The new
layer is responsible for controlling the IaaS below it as well as exposing its own APIs to be controlled by a consumer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Infrastructure that is managed by software is a key differentiator in the cloud. Software-controlled infrastructure
enables infrastructure to scale, and it also plays a role in resiliency, provisioning, and maintainability. The software
needs to be aware of the infrastructure’s abstractions and know how to take an abstract resource and implement it in
consumable IaaS components accordingly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="open-source-and-government">Open Source and Government&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Government should build technology that uses open standards to ensure your system works and communicates with other
products or systems, and can easily be upgraded and expanded.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adopting and using &lt;strong>open standards&lt;/strong> means you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Move between different technologies when you need to, avoiding vendor lock-in&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Quickly and easily change your service when you need to&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Increase compatibility with all stakeholders&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open up the range of companies you can purchase from as more of them are likely to use the same standard as you&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Access a wider range of both open source and proprietary software vendors&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Our choices for hosting infrastructure, databases, software frameworks, programming languages and the rest of the
technology stack should seek to avoid vendor lock-in and match what successful modern consumer and enterprise software
companies would choose today. In particular, digital services teams should consider using open source software,
cloud-based, and commodity solutions across the technology stack, because of their widespread adoption and support by
successful consumer and enterprise technology companies in the private sector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open source software (OSS) tends to use and help define open standards and publicly available specifications. OSS
products are, by their nature, publicly available specifications, and the availability of their source code promotes
open, democratic debate around their specifications, making them both more robust and interoperable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using open source software means you can benefit from:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Solving common problems with readily available open source technology&lt;/li>
&lt;li>More time and resource for customized solutions to solve the rare or unique problems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lower implementation and operational running costs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>